Guide to the James S. Trefil papers, 1965-2009
George Mason University Libraries
- James Trefil papers
  - NASA Captions Project- [Sea Surface Temperature]- Altimeter- [Biosphere]- [Pacific Zoom]- [Ozone]- [LIMS]- [ERBE]- [MSU (El Nino)]- [SAGE]- [Morter File- NASA] (Folder 4-14, Box 37)
  - 1988-89 Travel (Folder 1, Box 38)
  - The Chicago Academy of Sciences (Folder 2, Box 38)
  - Original Extinction Piece (1981) (Folder 3, Box 38)
  - SPM/Discover (Folder 4, Box 38)
  - General Magazine Correspondence (Folder 5, Box 38)
  - Long-Term Sun-Weather Relationships (Folder 6, Box 38)
  - Earth (Folder 7, Box 38)
  - Seminars- Earth (Folder 8, Box 38)
  - Deep Mines [Deep Mines Story] (Folder 9, Box 38)
  - S.M. Galaxy (Folder 10, Box 38)
  - Q. Mech- Smithsonian (Folder 11, Box 38)
  - Canals of Mars (Folder 12, Box 38)
  - Sheldon (Folder 13, Box 38)
  - Tombaugh Column (Folder 14, Box 38)
  - U.S.A. Weekend- Pending- Dolly- Adler- Millennium- Breast Cancer (Folder 1-6, Box 39)
  - U.S.A. Weekend Back File (Folder 7, Box 39)
  - Trefil Articles (Folder 8-9, Box 39)
  - Second Edition of Scientific Literacy (Folder 1, Box 40)
  - Correspondence 1998-2000 (Folder 2, Box 40)
  - Antimatter (Folder 3-5, Box 40)
  - Atoms to Quarks (First Draft)- Outline, Chapters 1 and 2 (Folder 1, Box 41)
  - Atoms to Quarks (First Draft)- Chapters 3 through 14 (Folder 2-7, Box 41)
  - A Scientist at the Seashore (Edited Copy)- Copyright Pages and Call-Out Sheets (Folder 8, Box 41)
  - A Scientist at the Seashore (Edited Copy)- Introduction, Chapters 1 through 12 (Folder 9-14, Box 41)
  - A Scientist at the Seashore (Edited Copy)- Chapter 13 and Caption Manuscript (Folder 15, Box 41)
  - Meditation at 10,000 Feet (First Draft)- Introduction and Chapter 1 (Folder 1, Box 42)
  - Meditation at 10,000 Feet (First Draft)- Chapters 2 through 13 (Folder 2-7, Box 42)
  - Meditation at 10,000 Feet (First Draft)- Chapter 15 and Running Head Copy (Folder 8, Box 42)
  - Meditation at 10,000 Feet (First Draft)- Photo Caption Copy, Callouts, Illustrations, Indices (Folder 9, Box 42)
  - Meditation at 10,000 Feet (Edited)- Introduction and Chapters 1 through 14 (Folder 10-16, Box 42)
  - Time, Space, Infinity (Rough Draft)- Prologue, Chapter 1, 2, and 3 (Folder 1, Box 43)
  - Time, Space, Infinity (Rough Draft)- Chapter 1, Part 3- Chapter 2, Part 3- Chapter 3, Part 3- Chapter 4, Part 3- Chapter 1, Part 4- Chapter 1, Part 5 (Folder 2-7, Box 43)
  - Time, Space, Infinity (Rough Draft)- Chapter 2, Part 5- Chapter 3, Part 5- Chapter 4, Part 5- Part 6- Chapter 1, Part 6 (Folder 8-13, Box 43)
  - Time, Space, Infinity (Edited)- Chapters 1 -18 (Folder 15-22, Box 43)
  - Time, Space, Infinity (Edited)- Epilogue (Folder 23, Box 43)
  - "Crater Taphonomy and Bombardment Rates in the Phanerozoic" (Folder 1-2, Box 44)
  - Cratering Data (Folder 3-5, Box 44)
  - David M. Raup Articles (Folder 6, Box 44)
  - Crater Decay File (Folder 7, Box 44)
  - Fossil Record (Folder 1, Box 45)
  - Target Rock (Folder 2, Box 45)
  - Impact Effects (Folder 3, Box 45)
  - Surface Removal Paper (Folder 4, Box 45)
  - Surface Removal (Folder 5, Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous Readings (Folder 6-7, Box 45)
  - Correspondence 1986- August 1987 (Move to GMU) (Folder 1-2, Box 46)
  - Job Search Letters 1985-86 (Folder 3, Box 46)
  - Calculation Log (Folder 4, Box 46)
  - Planet Size (Folder 5, Box 46)
  - Search Documents (Folder 6, Box 46)
  - Papers (1986) (Folder 7, Box 46)
  - Manuscript Notes- Country Roads (Folder 8, Box 46)
  - Articles (Folder 9-10, Box 46)
  - Correspondence 1991-92 (Folder 1-2, Box 47)
  - Correspondence 1992-94 (Folder 3-5, Box 47)
  - Quantum Field Theory: Mandl Notes (Folder 1, Box 48)
  - Quantum Field Theory: I, II, III (Folder 2-4, Box 48)
  - Quantum Mechanics: Q. Mech. I, II, III (Folder 5-7, Box 48)
  - Nuclear and Many Body Theory: Many Body Seminar (Folder 1, Box 49)
  - Nuclear and Many Body Theory: Nuclear I, II (Folder 2-3, Box 49)
  - Nuclear and Many Body Theory: Many Body Theory (Folder 4, Box 49)
  - Nuclear and Many Body Theory: Nuclear (Folder 5, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Articles (Folder 6, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Impulse Approx. (Folder 7, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Wick, RMP (Folder 8, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Scweber, Ch. 12 (Folder 9, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: He3 Work (Folder 10, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Publication of Results (Folder 11-12, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Numerical Results (Folder 13, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: O18 Work (Folder 14, Box 49)
  - Pion Double Charge Exchange Scattering From Nuclei: Miscellaneous (Folder 15, Box 49)
  - General Theory of Relativity: Gen. Rel. I, II (Folder 1-3, Box 50)
  - Introduction to Theoretical Physics: Theoret I, II, III (Folder 4-6, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Anglo Saxon (Folder 7, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Russian 52 (Folder 8, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Russian 10 (Folder 9, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Renaissance Art (Folder 10, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Rel. Kinematics (Folder 11, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Slavic Ethnogenisis (Folder 12, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Biophys. (Folder 13, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Phil. Sci. (Folder 14, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Orals (Folder 15, Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous: Comprehensive (Folder 16, Box 50)
  - [Course Notes] Depolarization- Counting- Integrals- Closure Results- Program Notes- Miscellaneous- Nx Exchange (Folder 1-7, Box 51)
  - [Course Notes] Work on Proofs- P Photo Prod. A Dep.- P Exchange- Numerical Results- Data- Helcity- Reading Notes (Folder 8-14, Box 51)
  - [Miscellaneous] (Folder 1-4, Box 52)
  - [Mathematics] (Folder 5-7, Box 52)
  - Physics- Heat, Sound, and Light- Electricity and Magnetism- Basic Mechanics (Folder 1-3, Box 53)
  - Mathematics- Real Variables, Differential Equations II (Folder 4, Box 53)
  - Mathematics- Complex Var. (Folder 5, Box 53)
  - Nuclear Theory Physics 341 (Stanford University Winter Quarter 1965, J. D. Walecka) (Folder 6, Box 53)
  - Nuclear Theory III Physics 342 (Stanford University Spring Quarter 1965, J. D. Walecka) (Folder 7, Box 53)
  - Theory of Many Particle Systems Physics 340 (Stanford University Fall Quarter 1965 J. D. Walecka) (Folder 8, Box 53)
  - Notes- J. Trefil Merton Coll. Oxford (Folder 9, Box 53)
  - [Notes] (Folder 10, Box 53)
  - Geoghysics Notes- Inverse Problem- Articles- Seminar Notes (Folder 1-3, Box 54)
  - Physics Thermodynamics (Folder 4, Box 54)
  - General Physics Teaching- Light and Heat- Miscellaneous- E and M- Mechanics (Folder 5-8, Box 54)
  - Third International Conference on High Energy Physics and Nuclear Structure (Folder 9, Box 54)
  - A Century of Physics at the University of Illinois 1868-1968 (Folder 10, Box 54)
  - The Arrow of Time (Folder 11, Box 54)
  - Study Guide for Home Energy Evaluation (Folder 12, Box 54)
  - Reserve Physics No.102 (Folder 13, Box 54)
  - An Article from Scientific American (July 1971, Vol.225, No.1) (Folder 14, Box 54)
  - All You Zombies (Reserve 104- Dr. Trefil) (Folder 15, Box 54)
  - Math. Methods (Folder 16, Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 17, Box 54)
  - SI Work (Practice Problems) (Folder 18, Box 54)
  - SI Reading (Practice Problems) (Folder 19, Box 54)
  - SI Articles (Practice Problems) (Folder 20, Box 54)
  - Spin 3/2 Isobar Problem (Practice Problems) (Folder 21, Box 54)
  - Report on Berkeley Heavy Fon Conference (Folder 22, Box 54)
  - Oxford Notes- Philosophy of Science- Modern Physics- Nuclear- E and M- Math. and Miscellaneous (Folder 1-5, Box 55)
  - Oxford Notes- Solid State- Kinetic Theory- Thermodynamic Statistical Mech.- Properties of Matter- Exams Misc. (Folder 6-10, Box 55)
  - Conservation and Wilderness (Folder 1, Box 56)
  - Snowflakes (Folder 2, Box 56)
  - DNA Repair (Folder 3, Box 56)
  - Column Ideas (Folder 4, Box 56)
  - Snowball Earth (Folder 5, Box 56)
  - Flood (Folder 6, Box 56)
  - Daniel Schrag (Folder 7, Box 56)
  - Airplane I, II (Folder 8-9, Box 56)
  - Methanol Fuel Cells (Folder 10, Box 56)
  - Cloning (Folder 11, Box 56)
  - U of C Talks (Folder 12, Box 56)
  - Newfoundland (Folder 13, Box 56)
  - Kalamazoo (Folder 14, Box 56)
  - Kalamazoo Talk (Folder 15, Box 56)
  - The New York Academy of Sciences (Folder 16, Box 56)
  - Japan (Folder 17, Box 56)
  - IFI 1995 Nagoya (Folder 18, Box 56)
  - Anthropic (Folder 1, Box 57)
  - Then/Now (Folder 2, Box 57)
  - Guide to the Molecular Century (Folder 3, Box 57)
  - Dictionary of Cultural Literacy- 3rd Edition (Folder 4, Box 57)
  - Nitrogen (Back File) (Folder 5-6, Box 57)
  - Spectroscopy (Folder 7, Box 57)
  - Stonehenge (Folder 8, Box 57)
  - Parallax (Folder 9, Box 57)
  - The Inflationary Universe (Folder 10, Box 57)
  - Ancient Astronomers (Folder 11, Box 57)
  - Inflation (Folder 12, Box 57)
  - Stellar Fusion (Folder 13, Box 57)
  - H-R Diagrams (Folder 14, Box 57)
  - The Pierre Auger Project- Design Report November 1996 (Folder 1, Box 58)
  - Cosmic Rays (Folder 2, Box 58)
  - Judge's School 1996 (Palm Springs) (Folder 3, Box 58)
  - Judge's School 1998 (Folder 4, Box 58)
  - Ames (Folder 5, Box 58)
  - BRITT (Folder 6, Box 58)
  - Communities (Folder 7, Box 58)
  - Kansas City Museum (Folder 8, Box 58)
  - Davos (Folder 1-2, Box 59)
  - Davos 1998 (Folder 3, Box 59)
  - Davos 1999 (Folder 4-5, Box 59)
  - Davos Global Issues Group- London 200 (Folder 6, Box 59)
  - Davos 2000 (Folder 7, Box 59)
  - Davos Global Issues Group 2001 (Folder 8, Box 59)
  - Davos 2001 (Folder 9, Box 59)
  - World Economic Forum- Annual Meeting 2001 Report (Folder 10, Box 59)
  - Davos 2002 (Folder 11, Box 59)
  - World Economic Forum- Global City Initiative (Folder 12, Box 59)
  - First Americans (Folder 1, Box 60)
  - Physics Free Press (Folder 2, Box 60)
  - Study Guide for Home Energy Evaluation (Folder 3, Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (Folder 4, Box 60)
  - Thermodynamics of Strong Interactions by R. Hagedorn (Folder 5, Box 60)
  - Cumulative Control Study (Folder 6, Box 60)
  - [Physics and the Life Sciences]- Introduction- 2. Introduction to Mechanics- 3. Statics- 4. Dynamics- 5. Gravity- 6. Elasticity and Simple Harmonic Motion- 7. Introduction to Fluids and Hydrostatics- 8. Hydrodynamics- 9. Heat-Temperature- 10. Thermodynamics (Folder 7-16, Box 60)
  - [Electricity]- Some Basic Facts About Electricity- Electrical Properties of Materials- Introduction to Electrical Circuits- Solid State Devices and Electronics- Magnetism- Circuitry- Waves: Simple Harmonic Motion and Waves (Folder 17-23, Box 60)
  - 1991- 92 Travels (Folder 1, Box 61)
  - APS Public Info. Committee (Folder 2, Box 61)
  - Cosmic Multiplication Jpp: Cosmic Ray Multiplicity (Folder 3, Box 61)
  - Cosmic Multiplication Jpp: Jpp From Cosmic Ray Data (Folder 4, Box 61)
  - The Soviet Effort in Experimental High Energy Physics: Preliminary Draft- Journals- Reading Notes- Collaborations- Articles/Notes- Citations/Conf. (Folder 5-10, Box 61)
  - Marshall Committee (Folder 11-12, Box 61)
  - Tree Rings (Folder 1, Box 62)
  - Interconnected Earth (Folder 2-5, Box 62)
  - Waterfall- Corr. (Folder 6, Box 62)
  - Correspondence (Folder 7, Box 62)
  - Ideas IQ. Reports (Folder 8, Box 62)
  - HALE [Explorer of the Universe] (Folder 1-2, Box 63)
  - HALE [On the Probable Existence of a Magnetic Field in Sun-Spots] (Folder 3, Box 63)
  - HALE [Magnetic Observation of Sunspots] (Folder 4, Box 63)
  - Solar Astronomy, MEADOWS [Early Solar Physics] (Folder 5, Box 63)
  - Dark Matter (Folder 6, Box 63)
  - The University of Chicago, Department of the Geophysical Sciences Directory 1988- 1989 (Folder 7, Box 63)
  - Rotation Calc. (Folder 8, Box 63)
  - Int. Earth- S.M. (Folder 9, Box 63)
  - UVA Undergraduate Record 1985-86 (Folder 1, Box 64)
  - Physics (Folder 2, Box 64)
  - Environmental Sciences 150, 201, 148, 101, 115, 220, 250 (Folder 3-4, Box 64)
  - Chemistry (Folder 5, Box 64)
  - Biology (Folder 6, Box 64)
  - Astronomy (Folder 7, Box 64)
  - Faculty Reports From Dean Robert Kelloaa (Folder 8, Box 64)
  - Memo's on Meeting Schedule (Folder 9, Box 64)
  - Science Requirement Course Criteria (Folder 10, Box 64)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 11, Box 64)
  - Quantitative Reasoning (Folder 12, Box 64)
  - N- Designation (Folder 13, Box 64)
  - Charlottesville Bud Light Triathlon 10-4-86 (Folder 1, Box 65)
  - Physical Review Letters 09-28-70, 01-31-72 (Folder 2, Box 65)
  - Astro II (Folder 3-4, Box 65)
  - Large Angle/A-B Inclusive/TPM (Folder 5, Box 65)
  - Large P Inclusives (Folder 6, Box 65)
  - Modern Maturity (EXT) (Folder 1, Box 66)
  - Correspondence Oct. 1987-May 1988 (Folder 2-3, Box 66)
  - Activities File 1989-90 (Folder 4, Box 66)
  - [Sesquicentennial Associate Papers and Scholar at University of Chicago] (Folder 5, Box 66)
  - Fairbank (Folder 6, Box 66)
  - Pergamon Press Inc. [Royalty Info.] (Folder 7, Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous Old Stuff- UVA (Folder 8, Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 9, Box 66)
  - Conference on Non-Linear Dyn. (Folder 1, Box 67)
  - Pantheon Contract (Folder 2, Box 67)
  - Brittanica (Folder 3, Box 67)
  - NEH (Folder 4, Box 67)
  - Modern Maturity (Folder 5, Box 67)
  - McGraw- Hill Consulting (Folder 6, Box 67)
  - Levine School of Music (Folder 7, Box 67)
  - World Wildlife Fund (Folder 8, Box 67)
  - Brittanica 1987 (Folder 9, Box 67)
  - Correspondence 1988-89 (Folder 10, Box 67)
  - PREISS (Folder 1, Box 68)
  - World Book/Supernova (Folder 2, Box 68)
  - TTSRA (Folder 3, Box 68)
  - S.M. Travel- Toronto (Folder 4, Box 68)
  - Rainbow Conference (Folder 5, Box 68)
  - Quantum Conference (Folder 6, Box 68)
  - The Chicago Academy of Sciences (Folder 7, Box 68)
  - Senate Task Force (Folder 8, Box 68)
  - Publishers (Folder 9, Box 68)
  - Book Reviews 1985-87 (Folder 10, Box 68)
  - Craters/ S.M. (Folder 11-12, Box 68)
  - Analysis of Worlds in Collision (Folder 1, Box 69)
  - Physics in the 80's Overview (Folder 2, Box 69)
  - Lab Reports- Merton Coll. (Folder 3, Box 69)
  - Amplitudes (Folder 4, Box 69)
  - Baryon- Baryon Scattering (Folder 5, Box 69)
  - M-B Amplitudes (Folder 6, Box 69)
  - Meson- Baryon Formalisms- Books 1 nad 2 (Folder 7, Box 69)
  - Correspondence and Publication (Folder 8, Box 69)
  - Amplitude (Folder 9, Box 69)
  - Photoproduction Formalism (Folder 10, Box 69)
  - [Chodoke] Effect (Folder 1, Box 70)
  - Magnetic Tides (Folder 2, Box 70)
  - Lab Reports- Merton [College] (Folder 3, Box 70)
  - Production of Free Monopoles (Folder 4, Box 70)
  - Quark Production (Folder 5, Box 70)
  - Monoplonian (Folder 6, Box 70)
  - Cell Kinetics and Cancer Chemotherapy (Folder 7, Box 70)
  - Monopole and Quark Production (Folder 8, Box 70)
  - Seminar Notes (Folder 9, Box 70)
  - Monopolelonization: Papers, Eloss- Papers, General- Model (Folder 1-3, Box 71)
  - Rotating Fluids: Curvature- [Notes and Equations] (Folder 4-5, Box 71)
  - Technology: Fluidized Bed- Log Heat Conduction- Radiating Surface (Folder 6-8, Box 71)
  - The Urban Environment by Ian Douglas (Folder 1, Box 72)
  - Classical Physics (Folder 2-3, Box 72)
  - Classical E and M II (Folder 4-5, Box 72)
  - NAL Emulsion (Folder 1, Box 73)
  - E.A.S. (Folder 2, Box 73)
  - Scaling (Folder 3, Box 73)
  - Classical Physics Lecture Notes: Blood How-Seismic Waves- Properties of Solids- Atmospheric Motion- Viscosity and Heat Conduction- Spheres- Tides (Folder 4-10, Box 73)
  - Classical Physics Lecture Notes: Waves- Fluids in Motion- Rotating Gravitation Fluid- Equations of Motion- Notes for Next Year (Folder 11-15, Box 73)
  - Physical Review Letters (Folder 1, Box 74)
  - The American Oxonian (Folder 2, Box 74)
  - The Onion vs. The Bootstrap: Will We Ever Discover The Fundamental Nature of Matter? (Folder 3, Box 74)
  - Classical E and M: Electrostatics (Folder 4-5, Box 74)
  - Classical E and M Additional Notes: Articles- Exams- Problem Sets (Folder 6-8, Box 74)
  - Classical E and M: Radiation (Folder 9, Box 74)
  - Froissarta Bounds Factorization: R square N - Factorization - Frassert Bound (Folder 1-3, Box 75)
  - Medical Physics: Heart Valve- Urology Notes and Papers (Folder 4-5, Box 75)
  - Mathematical Physics (Folder 6-7, Box 75)
  - Misc. Research Topics: Red Shift- n-p Mass Difference- Spin in Quark Reactions- Multi-Glauber Notes- Superheavy Nuclei (Folder 1-5, Box 76)
  - Tumor Growth I: Table of Experiments 600-899- Sample Size Work- Fits to Growth Nerves- Cell Cycle Fits- Renewal Theory- Miscellaneous (Folder 6-11, Box 76)
  - Cultural Literacy 1987-88 (Folder 1-2, Box 77)
  - The Role of the Natural Sciences in Cultural Literacy (Folder 3, Box 77)
  - Dictionary Correspondence (Folder 4, Box 77)
  - [Newspaper Clippings on Cultural Literacy] (Folder 5, Box 77)
  - LIST (Folder 6, Box 77)
  - [Miscellaneous Cultural Literacy Papers] (Folder 7, Box 77)
  - [Achieving Scientific Literacy] (Folder 8, Box 77)
  - Scientific Literacy (Folder 9, Box 77)
  - Cultural Literacy (Folder 10, Box 77)
  - Unwritten Science Entries, Coded List, Tricia's Hunk of File 3A (Folder 1, Box 78)
  - A- A Dictionary of Cultural Literacy (Folder 2, Box 78)
  - Science/ Culture (Folder 3, Box 78)
  - Arnold Essay (Folder 4, Box 78)
  - 6th Chapter of Cultural Literacy (Folder 5, Box 78)
  - Individual and Society (Folder 6, Box 78)
  - "A's" of Cultural Literacy (Folder 7, Box 78)
  - Core Knowledge (Folder 8, Box 78)
  - Physical Science (Folder 9, Box 78)
  - Biology (Folder 10, Box 78)
  - [Science Essays for Cultural Literacy] (Folder 11, Box 78)
  - Science Word List (Folder 12, Box 78)
  - New Stuff for Wordlist (Folder 13, Box 78)
  - [Drafts of Table of Contents for Cultural Literacy] (Folder 1, Box 79)
  - Humanities I: Children's Literature (Folder 2, Box 79)
  - Revised Version of Ch.5- Thorndyke and Boker Everyday Classics (Folder 3, Box 79)
  - [Glossary] (Folder 4, Box 79)
  - Revised List of Clusters for 1988 Readers (Grades 2-8) (Folder 5, Box 79)
  - Dictionary Revision (Folder 6-7, Box 79)
  - [Draft of Glossary] (Folder 8, Box 79)
  - Core Knowledge (Folder 9, Box 79)
  - [Chapter 5 of Cultural Literacy] (Folder 10, Box 79)
  - DCL- Original Biology Test (Folder 11, Box 79)
  - Spin Effects in Light Nuclei: Parameters- Scattering- Quarks- Regge Amplitudes (Folder 1-5, Box 80)
  - [Extinction] (Folder 6, Box 80)
  - Seminar Notes- 1980 (Folder 7, Box 80)
  - 103- Labs- Class Handouts- US Energy River- Mechanics- Lecture Notes- Reading Notes- Plans for Class (Folder 8-14, Box 80)
  - Climate/ Weather (Folder 15, Box 80)
  - [Book Covers] (Folder 16, Box 80)
  - Nat. Geo. Book File (Folder 1, Box 81)
  - World Book (Folder 2, Box 81)
  - Time (Folder 3, Box 81)
  - US AW- Current (Folder 4, Box 81)
  - Activity Summary Backfile (Folder 5, Box 81)
  - Reports to the Nation: Our Ozone Shield, El Nino and Climate Prediction, the Climate System (Folder 6, Box 81)
  - [Scientific Magazine Articles] (Folder 7-9, Box 81)
  - Managing Gala (Folder 10, Box 81)
  - Nature (Folder 11, Box 81)
  - Nature Book (Folder 12, Box 81)
  - Sci. Lit. Test/ Backfile (Folder 13, Box 81)
  - Meteorites (Folder 1, Box 82)
  - SSC File (Folder 2, Box 82)
  - Star Trek (Folder 3, Box 82)
  - Royalty Statements (Folder 4-5, Box 82)
  - EXP TV Course (Folder 6, Box 82)
  - NAS Content Standards (Folder 7, Box 82)
  - Correspondence 1994-98 (Folder 8, Box 82)
  - Center for the New West (Folder 9, Box 82)
  - Astrology (Folder 10, Box 82)
  - Whale Feet/Discover (Folder 1, Box 83)
  - City (Folder 2, Box 83)
  - Europa (Folder 3, Box 83)
  - Robinson 1998 Report (Folder 4, Box 83)
  - National Public Radio (Folder 5, Box 83)
  - Activities 1998-99 (Folder 6, Box 83)
  - Robinson Miscellaneous (Folder 7, Box 83)
  - Activity Report 1997-98 (Folder 8, Box 83)
  - PAGE (Folder 9, Box 83)
  - Judge's School (Folder 10, Box 83)
  - Robinson Report 1997 (Folder 11, Box 83)
  - Judge's School 1999 (Folder 12, Box 83)
  - Activities 1990-91 (Folder 13, Box 83)
  - Activities Backfile (Folder 14, Box 83)
  - Honors Science (Folder 15, Box 83)
  - Activities 1999-2000 (Folder 16, Box 83)
  - Sun (Folder 1, Box 84)
  - Biosphere (Folder 2, Box 84)
  - Consulting (Folder 3, Box 84)
  - Texas Symposium- 1996 (Folder 4, Box 84)
  - VFH (Folder 5, Box 84)
  - DNA Repair (Folder 6-7, Box 84)
  - [Moment of Creation Correspondence] (Folder 8, Box 84)
  - Red Lodge File (Folder 9, Box 84)
  - Making Fence (Folder 10, Box 84)
  - Fermi Column (Folder 11, Box 84)
  - Universe Articles (Folder 12, Box 84)
  - World Book (Folder 13, Box 84)
  - NPR- Commentaries (Folder 14, Box 84)
  - Column on Creativity (Folder 1, Box 85)
  - Q. GRAV (Folder 2, Box 85)
  - Evolution and Windows (Folder 3, Box 85)
  - Physics 343 Sect. A, Dr. Lazarus James Trefil (Folder 4, Box 85)
  - Tolls on "Grounds for Dismissal"/SUNSPOT (Folder 5, Box 85)
  - Chaos and SETI (Folder 6, Box 85)
  - Centrifuge Lecture (Folder 7, Box 85)
  - Nuclear Shadowing (Folder 8, Box 85)
  - Tachyon Seminar (Folder 9, Box 85)
  - Sm. Nov. 1990- Column/Fossils (Folder 10, Box 85)
  - Early Universe- Hot (Folder 11, Box 85)
  - Two Cultures (Folder 12, Box 85)
  - Talk- Tests of G.R. (Folder 13, Box 85)
  - Dark Matter (Folder 14, Box 85)
  - Physics Teacher- Thick Films (Folder 1, Box 86)
  - Sci. Dig.- Steel (Folder 2, Box 86)
  - Norton (Folder 3, Box 86)
  - The Sciences (Folder 4, Box 86)
  - National Geographic (Folder 5, Box 86)
  - Scribner's- Elementary Particles (Folder 6, Box 86)
  - Space Colony (Folder 7, Box 86)
  - 1982-84 Correspondence (Folder 8, Box 86)
  - Science Digest (Folder 1, Box 87)
  - ETI Outline/ Correspondence (Folder 2, Box 87)
  - S. M. (Folder 3, Box 87)
  - Evaluation- 1982 (Folder 4, Box 87)
  - S.M.- Probability (Folder 5, Box 87)
  - AAAS/ W.M. Award (Folder 6, Box 87)
  - Tucson Visit/ Tree Rings (Folder 7, Box 87)
  - Nazca (Folder 8, Box 87)
  - U of Virginia (Folder 9, Box 87)
  - Mountains (Folder 10, Box 87)
  - Correspondence- 1986 (Folder 1, Box 88)
  - NSF Grant (Folder 2, Box 88)
  - Keller Book (Folder 3, Box 88)
  - Pyramid (Folder 4, Box 88)
  - Unfinished Education (Folder 5, Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous Stuff From Old Folders (Folder 6, Box 88)
  - Smithsonian Books (Folder 7, Box 88)
  - NSF Renewal (Folder 1, Box 89)
  - Progress Reports- U of I (Folder 2, Box 89)
  - Skipping Stone (Folder 3, Box 89)
  - Brontosaurus (Folder 4, Box 89)
  - Bow and Arrow (Folder 5, Box 89)
  - Brittanica (Folder 6, Box 89)
  - Proposals (Folder 7, Box 89)
  - Cottrell (Folder 8, Box 89)
  - VISTAS (Folder 9, Box 89)
  - Science Digest (Folder 10, Box 89)
  - Big Bang (Folder 11, Box 89)
  - [World Economic Forum Participants] (Folder 1, Box 90)
  - World Economic Forum Meetings- 2000, 1999, 1998, 1997, 1995 (Folder 2-6, Box 90)
  - Formanek (Folder 7, Box 90)
  - Wine Log (Folder 8, Box 90)
  - World Economic Forum- Davos Switzerland Souvenir Menu (Folder 9, Box 90)
  - Cassell A- Z (Folder 1-3, Box 91)
  - Editserve.co.uk (Folder 4, Box 91)
  - Classification of Headwords (Folder 5, Box 91)
  - Cassell BW (Folder 6, Box 91)
  - Chessell Business (Folder 1, Box 92)
  - Correspondence (Folder 2, Box 92)
  - Laws of Nature: Classification of Headwords (Folder 3, Box 92)
  - Running Totals II (Folder 4, Box 92)
  - Cassell (Folder 5, Box 92)
  - Preface (Folder 6, Box 92)
  - The Alvarez Hypothesis (Folder 7, Box 92)
  - Cassell Revision I (Folder 8, Box 92)
  - 3rd Batch of Entries (Folder 9, Box 92)
  - S- Cond (Folder 1, Box 93)
  - Correspondence- 1976, 1975, 1974, 1973, 1972 (Folder 2-8, Box 93)
  - Dark Matter: Massive V- Strings- Seminars- Supersym- Dark Matter- Structure- Eastern Conf.- Texas Symp.- Dark Matter, Galaxies, and Large Scale Structure in the Universe (Folder 9, Box 94)
  - Astronomy 106 (Folder 10-12, Box 94)